[Netero] Wait.
Exchanging words?
Hey, King…
would you like to know your name?
I bet I'm the only one who knows now.
Those same subordinates probably died
fighting your Royal Guard.
[wind blowing]
I'll make you a deal.
If you can force me to admit defeat,
I'll tell you your name.
[King] Force you?
But without killing you?
[scoffs]
[tense music playing]
So I'll be playing
without a rook and bishop.
[opening theme music playing]
[singer singing in Japanese]
[singer singing in English]
CENTIPEDE X AND X MEMORY
[narrator] As the King and Netero prepared
for what they were both certain
would be their final battle…
[dramatic music playing]
[narrator] Ikalgo continued to cry
deep beneath the palace,
[Ikalgo sobbing]
[remote beeps]
[Ikalgo continues sobbing]
I have to do this.
I have to!
[gags]
This is no time for tears.
I have to find Palm.
[gasps]
The door to the warehouse area is open.
[Welfin] I've got a lot
of questions I wanna ask you,
but if you try anything funny,
you're dead.
[Ikalgo] I've got a pretty good idea
about what he wants to know…
And he'll use any means necessary
to find out.
If I start leaking information,
people could die.
But if he's a Manipulator,
he can obtain the information
against my will.
Huh? Stop right there.
I really will kill you!
[Ikalgo] Kill me, then.
That's what I want.
Stop now!
[Ikalgo] I won't betray my friends,
but I'll take you with me!
[screams]
[Welfin] Now you've done it, you bastard!
Missileman!
[whimpers]
[groans]
[Ikalgo] Hey, I'm not dead.
I didn't sustain any damage.
What was that attack?
[Welfin] Ah, damn it.
That really hurts.
Why, you little punk.
You'll pay for this.
That bastard.
I'll take my time beating him to a pulp.
[chuckles]
[Ikalgo] Wait. He planted
something living inside me?
-[crunch]
-[groans]
They grow by feeding
on your defiance, so get ready.
[groaning]
If you disobey my orders
Huh?
Hey, what are you doing, idiot?
Didn't you listen to a word I just said?
If you try what I think
you're going to try…
[gasping]
All that's fine by me.
And if I die, so be it.
[inhales]
Ahh! No!
No, stop!
[Ikalgo groaning]
[Welfin] Wait a minute.
If he wanted to kill me,
that's the ultimate form of resistance.
Now it'll take no time at all
for the black centipedes to grow
large enough to kill him.
I just need to make sure you stay put.
I still have ammunition.
[tense music playing]
Don't mess with me, bastard!
You are so dead.
I'll kill you, you hear me!
-[inhales]
-[Welfin screaming]
[groaning]
[centipedes clattering]
[Ikalgo laughing]
[Welfin] Huh?
[tense music playing]
[centipedes rustling]
[dramatic music playing]
[imperceptible]
I get it, okay?
Look, I won't go anywhere! I promise!
I give up, so, please, don't shoot.
[Ikalgo] The pain is going away.
The creatures inside me are in agony?
[Welfin] Damn it. You win.
I saw it coming.
I just had a feeling
this would happen eventually.
who didn't have any regard
for their own life.
so do you think you could
get rid of all these bugs now?
[Welfin groans] Shut the hell up.
I'm in too much pain
to think about that right now.
Hmm?
[groans]
Uh…
Hurry up, will you?
[Welfin] Just give me a minute.
Damn, I don't have a way
to deactivate Missileman.
But if I tell him the truth,
I'm in real trouble.
How am I gonna get out of this?
[tense music playing]
I need to buy some time.
-[centipedes rustling]
-[Ikalgo growls]
[Ikalgo] Then hurry up,
and get rid of these things.
[Welfin chuckles nervously]
Well, I, um…
[Ikalgo] Hmm?
[groans]
Oh, well. Forget it.
No, wait! Hold on a minute!
I can't remove them now,
not once they've been activated.
Sorry, but it's true.
[Ikalgo] The insects are in pain again.
Thing is, I only attack to kill someone,
and screw what happens next.
I never gave a single thought
to what happened to my enemy afterwards.
Huh?
[Ikalgo] I once knew someone
just like him.
I'm curious.
[groans]
[dramatic music playing]
[Welfin] Fine. You win.
When I woke up, my first thought was…
[sighs]
Damn it.
I still remember it like it was yesterday.
[automatic guns firing]
[Welfin] Those monster bugs
killed me in the NGL.
And soon, I was reborn as something new.
Even now, I can still remember
the one thing that…
that I most wanted to forget…
The sight of my father strangling me,
and the woman behind him just watching.
In the beginning,
I only had little flashbacks of it,
but over time, I remembered
everything that happened.
My little brother saved me…
even though we weren't related by blood.
He looked just like…
Gyro does!
[gasps] Gyro?
You know him as the King.
We used to fight
about whose life was worse.
When I had to laugh to keep from crying,
he was always there.
We were both empty,
and I guess, looking back,
that's why we had nothing to hide.
[sighs]
Sometimes I wonder what he's doing.
Oh. Those weaklings wanted
the treasure in the back,
so I let them in.
Don't worry. They're not a threat.
I was watching you and Blo on the monitor,
[Ikalgo gags]
[Ikalgo sobbing]
[Ikalgo] I'm a coward!
[sobbing]
[Welfin] That's all.
Once I saw that you couldn't finish Blo,
I figured you'd be an easy target,
but now I see I was wrong.
[sighs]
You go ahead.
I'm way too tired.
[Ikalgo] One last question.
Did you see a woman in the palace?
A woman?
They called it Number One.
[sighs]
Thanks a lot!
Hmm.
[narrator] Welfin had spent his life
unable to trust himself or others.
Telling Ikalgo the location
of the woman he was searching for
was the first time he had
ever opened up to someone,
spoken from the heart, and told the truth.
[cracking]
[fluid sloshing]
[closing theme music playing]
[Gon] What's wrong, Killua?